Pete Welding collection, 1958-1995
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 8: Sound recordings
  - Subseries 1: Artists, bands, and interviews
    - Idella Jones - Big Joe Williams, reel #2, August 20, 1963, AFC 2011/053: SR232; RAA 58382; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:21:21): analog, 15 ips, full track, mono; 7 in.
      00:18:09 "Drinking of the Wine, Wine, Wine"
      00:21:21 End
    - Quincy Jones Orchestra, 1957, 1976, AFC 2011/053: SR459; RXH 4699; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:38:56, Side 2: 00:35:20): analog, 7 1/2 ips, stereo; 7 in.
      Logger's note: The first half includes songs from Quincy Jones's album Go West, Man! (ABC-186; released 1957). The second half includes songs from Quincy Jones's album This Is How I Feel About Jazz (ABC-149; released 1976).
      Start "Dancin' Pants" [from the album Go West, Man! ]
      00:03:59 "Blues Day" [from the album Go West, Man! ]
      00:08:30 "Bright Moon" [from the album Go West, Man! ]
      00:13:35 "No Bones at All" [from the album Go West, Man! ]
      00:17:28 "The Oom Is Blues" [from the album Go West, Man! ]
      00:22:29 "Be My Guest" [from the album Go West, Man! ]
      00:26:43 Medley: "What's New"/"We'll Be Together Again"/ "Time on My Hands"/"You Go to My Head"/"Laura" [from the album Go West, Man! ]
      00:32:48 "London Derriere" [from the album Go West, Man! ]
      00:36:42 "Kings Road Blues" (the above song ends abruptly)[from the album Go West, Man! ]
      Start "Walkin'" [from the album This Is How I Feel About Jazz ]
      00:10:25 "A Sleepin' Bee" [from the album This Is How I Feel About Jazz ]
      00:15:00 "Sermonette" [from the album This Is How I Feel About Jazz ]
      00:20:48 "Stockholm Sweetnin'" [from the album This Is How I Feel About Jazz ]
      00:26:13 "Evening in Paris" [from the album This Is How I Feel About Jazz ]
      00:30:12 "Boo's Bloos" [from the album This Is How I Feel About Jazz ]
      00:35:20 End
    - Buell Kazee, July 5, 1967, AFC 2011/053: SR298; RXH 4184; 1 sound tape reel (00:26:29): analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in.
      Recorded at UCLA. Collector's original ID number: 80.
      Start Medley of dance tunes
      00:03:03 "Dance Around My Pretty Little Miss"
      00:04:13 "Barbara Allen"
      00:10:08 "The Wife Of Usher's Well"
      00:15:39 "John Hardy"
      00:19:17 "East Virginia"
      00:22:11 "Madam, I Have Come A'Courting" (2 verses longer than FS-3810)
      00:24:20 "When My Mother Wields The Shingle"
      00:26:29 End
    - Peck Kelley and Lynn "Son" Harrell, undated, AFC 2011/053: SR569; RXH 5430; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Collector's original ID number: 60.
    - Kennedy Corrido dubs, circa 1964 and after, AFC 2011/053: SR475; RXH 4715; 1 sound tape reel (00:22:45): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      See SR638.
      Start "Homenaje a J.F. Kennedy" (Jose A. Morante) - Los Conquisadores (Norteño LP803)
      00:04:04 "Tragedia de Kennedy" (Domingo Villarreal), Trio Los Amigos (Valman 45 #28)
      00:07:31 "Lamento a Kennedy" (Gilberto Lopez) G. Lopez. (Ideal 45 #1315). Includes a false start.
      00:10:54 "Corrido De Kennedy" (Ray Pérez Y Soto) - Lupita Y Ray (Falcon 45 #1315)
      00:14:21 "A Kennedy en Vida" (Guadalupe Saucedo) - Trio Internacional (Homenaje 45 #01)
      00:17:18 "En Honor a Kennedy" (Gaston Ponce Castellanos) - Trio Internacional (Homenaje 45 #01)
      00:20:00 "America de Luto" (P.N. Isaza) - Carlos Gonzales (Ideal 45 #2128)
      00:22:45 End
    - Kennedy Songs (dubs) / Insert, undated, AFC 2011/053: SR638; RXH 5515; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      See SR475.
    - George Kennedy and Jimmy Walker #1, October 6, 1962, AFC 2011/053: SR299; RXH 4185; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:23:37): analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in.
      Vendor's digitization note: The Side 1 program is distorted at times, and there are speed fluctuations.
      Start Fragment of "What'd I Say" accompanied by guitar
      00:02:58 "Things That I Used to Do" (accompanied by guitar and piano)
      00:06:40 Let's Go Out Boogying in the Park
      00:10:36 "Goin' Back to Texas"
      00:16:00 An unidentified blues song. Lyrics: "Something about my Jesus, kind of sweet, oh listen to my prayer, everyday come along, passing by, every day of my life God lives with me"
      00:19:23 Fragment of unidentified songs.
      00:19:58 "Everyday I Have The Blues"
      00:23:37 End
    - "In Concert" - B.B. King (November 23, 1973); Bobby Bland (December 14, 1973); Ike and Tina Turner (December 14, 1973), November 23, 1973, December 14, 1973, AFC 2011/053: SR160; RXH 4043; 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:34:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.
      Archivist's note: The ABC-TV show "In Concert" featured concert performances that were recorded live and subsequently broadcast. The dates given are probably broadcast dates.
      Start B.B. King (BK) performs "Every Day I Have the Blues"
      00:01:35 The next instrumental selection
      00:04:35 BK performs "How Blue Can You Get (Downhearted)"
      00:07:03 The next selection by BK titled "To Know You Is To Love You"
      00:10:29 BK introduces his band
      00:11:57 BK performs his last selection at this concert called "Somebody Loves You"
      00:14:07 Bobby "Blue" Bland (BB) performs "Turn on Your Lovelight"
      00:16:56 BB performs "Stormy Monday Blues"
      00:21:54 BB introduces his band
      00:24:53 BB and his band perform "Drifting Blues"
      00:28:40 Ike and Tina Turner perform "I Smell Trouble"
    - B.B. King - unissued Chess sides, undated, AFC 2011/053: SR162; RXH 4045; 1 sound tape reel (backcoated polyester, 00:09:38): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.
      Start "Don't Keep Me Waiting"
      00:02:20 "Recession Blues"
      00:04:41 "Tickle Britches"
      00:07:15 "Don't Break Your Promise"
      00:09:38 End
    - Bob Kirkpatrick, undated, AFC 2011/053: SR236; RXH 4118; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:30:35): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in.
      Archivist's note: Live performance, in front of an audience.
      Start An unidentified man introduces Bob Kirkpatrick (as Robert Kirkpatrick; starts at 00:00:16)
      00:00:23 "Sad, Sad Blues"
      00:04:27 unidentified song #1
      00:08:09 unidentified song #2
      00:11:18 "Sweet Little Angel" (plus spoken introduction)
      00:17:17 unidentified song #3
      00:20:19 "Stormy Monday" (plus spoken introduction)
      00:30:35 End
    - Creed Taylor Presents Know Your Jazz, Vol. 1, 1956, AFC 2011/053: SR481; RXH 4721; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:38:42): analog, 7 1/2 ips, stereo; 7 in.
      Possibly dubbed from ABC-115 (vinyl record). See SR482 for the same content.
      Start "Indiana" by Billy Taylor
      00:02:24 "Embraceable You" - Jimmy Cleveland [trombone solo with the band]
      00:06:30 "The Nearness Of You" - Oscar Pettiford, bass solo with piano; drums; guitar
      00:10:40 "In A Mellow Tone" - Kenny Clarke [alto saxophone solo with the band]
      00:13:26 "If I Love Again" - Tony Scott [clarinet solo with the band]
      00:16:57 "There Will Never Be Another You" - Al Cohn [tenor saxophone solo with the band]
      00:21:05 "Laura" - Joe Roland [xylophone solo with the band]
      00:25:02 "But Not For Me" - Charlie Rouse [alto saxophone solo with the band]
      00:27:46 "How About You?" - Mundell Lowe
      00:31:10 "Stella by Starlight" - Donald Byrd [trumpet solo with the band]
      00:34:48 "Come Rain Or Come Shine" - Gigi Gryce [alto saxophone solo with the band]
      00:38:42 End
    - Creed Taylor Presents Know Your Jazz, Vol. 1, 1956, AFC 2011/053: SR482; RXH 4722; 1 sound tape reel (00:38:39): analog, 7 1/2 ips, stereo; 7 in.
      See SR481.
      00:00:24 "Indiana" by Billy Taylor [piano solo with the band]
      00:02:45 "Embraceable You" by Jimmy Cleveland [trombone solo with the band]
      00:06:50 "The Nearness of You" by Oscar Pettiford [bass solo with the band]
      00:10:56 "In A Mellow Tone" by Kenny Clarke [alto saxophone and drums solo with the band]
      00:13:40 "If I Love Again" by Tony Scott [clarinet solo with the band]
      00:17:09 "There Will Never Be Another You" by Al Cohn [tenor saxophone solo with the band]
      00:21:13 "Laura" by Joe Roland [xylophone solo with the band]
      00:25:10 "But Not For Me" by Charlie Rouse [saxophone solo with the band]
      00:27:52 "How About You?" by Mundell Lowe [electric guitar solo with the band]
      00:31:12 "Stella By Starlight" by Donald Byrd [trumpet solo with the band]
      00:34:49 "Come Rain or Come Shine" by Gigi Gryce [saxophone solo with the band]
      00:38:39 End
    - Lee Konitz - Stan Kenton - Rolf Billberg - Warne Marsh - Ted Brown, early 1950s, 1956, February 23, 1965, 1966, AFC 2011/053: SR578; RXH 5439; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 01:32:24, Side 2: 01:20:48): analog; 7 in.
      Side 1 - Stan Kenton, featuring Lee Konitz (early 1950s)
      Start Stan Kenton announces that it is Lee Konitz's night. He introduces the saxophonist Lee Konitz who will improvise to the chord progression of "Blue Moon."
      00:01:48 "Blue Moon"
      00:05:22 "My Lady"
      00:08:50 "In Lighter Vein"
      00:11:33 "Of All Things (All The Things You Are)"
      00:14:57 "My Funny Valentine"
      00:18:18 "Lover Man"
      00:21:10 "There's A Small Hotel"
      00:23:55 "I've Got You Under My Skin"
      00:26:48 "April In Paris"
      00:29:43 "Crazy Rhythm"
      Side 1 - Rolf Billberg, alto saxophone; Jan Allan, trumpet; Rune Gustafsson, guitar; Roman Dylag, bass; Rune Carlsson, drums (February 23, 1965)
      00:32:45 "Ablution"
      00:38:02 "We'll Be Together Again"
      00:44:47 "Fobic"
      00:48:55 "Nursery Rhyme"
      Side 1 - Rolf Billberg, alto saxophone; Allan Botschinsky, flugelhorn; Ole Molin, guitar; Neils-Henning Örsted Pedersen, bass; Rune Carlsson, drums (1966)
      00:54:48 "Sound-Lee"
      01:01:00 "Darn That Dream" by Lee Konitz
      01:10:08 "Palo Alto" by Lee Konitz
      Side 1 - Warne Marsh Quintet, with Ted Brown (1956); dubbed from the LP Modern Jazz Gallery (1956)
      01:17:13 "Bon Blew"
      01:20:57 "Time's Up"
      01:24:16 "Earful"
      01:29:05 "Black Jack"
      01:32:24 End
      Start An unidentified song #1 in Portuguese.
      00:02:40 An unidentified song #2 in Portuguese.
      00:06:08 An unidentified song #3 in Portuguese.
      00:08:58 An unidentified song #4 in Portuguese.
      00:10:42 An unidentified song #5 in Portuguese.
      00:14:12 An unidentified song #6 in Portuguese.
      00:16:52 An unidentified song #7 in Portuguese.
      00:19:02 An unidentified song #8 in Portuguese.
      00:23:11 An unidentified song #9 in Portuguese.
      00:26:04 An unidentified song #10 in Portuguese.
      00:28:43 An unidentified song #11 in Portuguese.
      00:30:44 An unidentified song #12 in Portuguese.
      00:33:24 An unidentified song #13 in Portuguese.
      00:37:56 An unidentified song #14 in Portuguese.
      00:40:30 An unidentified song #15 in Portuguese.
      00:43:35 An unidentified song #16 in Portuguese.
      00:45:36 An unidentified song #17 in Portuguese.
      00:50:20 An unidentified song #18 in Portuguese.
      00:52:54 An unidentified song #19 in Portuguese.
      00:54:53 An unidentified song #20 in Portuguese.
      00:58:40 An unidentified song #21 in Portuguese.
      00:01:05 An unidentified song #22 in Portuguese.
      00:02:59 An unidentified song #23 in Portuguese.
      01:06:07 An unidentified jazz piece #1 played by the piano and the band.
      01:09:06 An unidentified jazz piece #2 played by the piano and the band.
      01:13:05 An unidentified jazz piece #3 played by the band.
      01:17:38 An unidentified jazz song. Lyrics: Winter in the dream, you are the handsome prince. I don't know how we careless fall so in love, so in love...
      01:20:48 End
    - Rubin Lacy church service #1, August 7, 1966, AFC 2011/053: SR107; RXH 3656; on one side of 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:28:15): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Logger's note: This is the first of four recordings of the Rev. Lacy (pastor) and the congregation of Union Baptist Church. See also SR108, SR109, and SR110. The recording quality of this SR is such that both spoken word and singing are very difficult to understand.
      Start Unintelligible talking
      00:00:47 singing, unidentified hymn
      00:02:17 RL reading from (the Bible)
      00:03:20 RL preaching
      00:04:25 RL leads singing of an unidentified hymn
      00:06:33 RL preaching, singing in background
      00:12:40 piano, unidentified hymn
      00:14:52 piano, unidentified hymn
      00:16:55 RL and congregation responsively read the 23rd psalm
      00:17:55 piano, unidentified hymn. RL calls for an offering
      00:22:00 piano, unidentified hymn
      00:25:06 piano, unidentified hymn
      00:27:42 RL talking
      00:28:14 End
    - Rubin Lacy church service #2, August 6, 1966, AFC 2011/053: SR108; RXH 3657; on one side of 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:21:06): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      See the note for SR107.
      Start RL preaching
      00:07:03 piano, unknown hymn
      00:13:30 piano, unknown hymn
      00:18:10 piano, unknown hymn, RL talking
      00:21:66 End
    - Rubin Lacy church service #3, August 6, 1966, AFC 2011/053: SR109; RXH 3658; on one side of 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:32:29): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Start RL talking
      00:00:58 piano, unknown hymn
      00:02:26 segue to "Amazing Grace"
      00:04:35 RL talking
      00:06:50 RL preaching
      00:32:29 End (RL's preaching not yet finished; continued on SR110 )
    - Rubin Lacy church service #4, August 6, 1966, AFC 2011/053: SR110; RXH 3659; on one side of 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:24:33): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Start RL preaching (continued from SR109 ). Piano in the background.
      00:07:28 RL and congregation sing unidentified hymn.
      00:10:06 RL recites "The Lord's Prayer" then prays. Congregation humming and singing in the background.
      00:13:09 unidentified hymn
      00:16:12 RL talking, singing in background.
      00:16:45 unidentified hymn with piano
      00:21:54 unidentified hymn with piano
      00:24:00 RL talking about taking a picture
      00:24:33 End
    - Rev. and Mrs. Rubin Lacy, August 6, 1966, AFC 2011/053: SR111; RXH 3660; on one side of 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:20:02): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Interview location: Ridgecrest, California.
      Start RL and ML sing ("Trying to Make Heaven My Home")
      00:00:56 RL and ML sing ("Let Jesus Lead You")
      00:04:19 RL and ML sing [first line] "All the Way, All the Way Lord"
      00:07:57 RL and ML sing [first line] "Oh Tell Me How You Felt When You Came Out of the Wilderness" [take 1]
      00:10:22 RL and ML sing [first line] "Oh Tell Me How You Felt When You Came Out of the Wilderness" [take 2]
      00:11:07 RL and ML sing [first line] "Oh Don't Worry About Me, Oh Don't Be Uneasy" [take 1]
      00:13:41 RL and ML sing [first line] "Oh Don't Worry About Me, Oh Don't Be Uneasy" [take 2]
      00:16:07 RL and ML sing [first line] "Hold to God's Gonna Changing Hands"
      00:20:02 End
    - Lazy River - rough mixes, undated, AFC 2011/053: SR780; RAA 59318; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - George Lewis Band, reel #2 of 3, circa 1953-1954, AFC 2011/053: SR233; RXH 4115; 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:32:50): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track stereo; 7 in.
      The full name of the group is the George Lewis Ragtime Jazz Band of New Orleans. This may be a dub copy of The Miami Folk Arts Society Presents The George Lewis Ragtime Jazz Band of New Orleans from the Oxford Series, v. 14, 2nd half. Recorded in front of a live audience. Part of a concert series. Collector's original ID number: 66.
      LC engineer's note: The tape is out of relative phase, which was corrected during transfer. The audio quality is very poor, yet is obviously in true stereo.
      Start Dr. John Ball is introduced, and he talks about the band and their music. Presentation of gifts to members of the band.
      00:06:19 Life membership cards for the Miami Folk Arts Society presented.
      00:09:19 George Lewis (?) announces "Just a Little Walk With Thee" and the band performs the song, in memory of Walter Jackson.
      00:18:24 "South Rampart Street Parade"
      00:21:24 unidentified tune
      00:25:41 "Walking With the King"
      00:30:21 "Ice Cream" (ends abruptly)
      00:32:50 End
    - Meade Lux Lewis, undated, AFC 2011/053: SR262; RXH 4144; 1 sound tape reel (Part 1: 00:15:34, Part 2: 00:15:51, Part 3: 00:15:57, Part 4: 00:15:49): analog, 15 ips, quarter track, mono; 7 in.
      Part 1
      00:03:40 unidentified tune #2
      00:07:50 unidentified tune #3
      00:11:07 unidentified tune #4
      00:12:53 unidentified tune #5 [before a live audience]
      00:15:34 End
      Part 2
      00:02:36 unidentified tune #2
      00:04:58 unidentified tune #3
      00:08:15 unidentified tune #4
      00:12:18 unidentified tune #5
      00:15:51 End
      Part 3
      00:03:02 unidentified tune #2
      00:05:26 unidentified tune #3
      00:09:22 unidentified tune #4
      00:13:05 unidentified tune #5
      00:15:57 End
      Part 4
      00:02:59 unidentified tune #2
      00:06:30 unidentified tune #3
      00:10:29 unidentified tune #4
      00:14:30 unidentified tune #5
      00:00:00 unidentified tune #6 [cut off abruptly]
      00:15:49 End
    - Meade Lux Lewis / Willie The Lion Smith - Piano Album / #8, undated, AFC 2011/053: SR609; RXH 5470; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - Shorty Rogers and His Giants, live at The Lighthouse, circa 1962, AFC 2011/053: SR579; RXH 5440; 1 sound tape reel (Channel 1: 00:28:47, Chanel 2: 00:31:40): analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in.
      Collector's original ID number: 67.
      Vendor's digitization note: The program is distorted at times. Channel 2 has audio break-up towards the end of the program.
      Archivist's note: Channels 3 and 4 have not been digitized, and may have no content. The tape box lists two songs ("Greensleeves" and "Tadd's Delight"), and has the words "lighthouse" and "jazz." These live recordings probably were made at The Lighthouse, a jazz club in Hermosa Beach, California. Towards the end of the first program a man introduces the band members: Lou Levy (piano), Gary Peacock (bass), Larry Bunker (drums), and Gary LeFebvre (tenor sax and flute). While the band itself is not named these musicians constituted the lineup for the group Shorty Rogers and His Giants, circa 1962.
      Start "Greensleeves"
      00:14:08 "Tadd's Delight"
      00:25:48 An unidentified jazz piece plays as an unidentified person introduces the band members: Pianist Lou Levy, bass player Gary Peacock, drums Larry Bunker and alto saxophone/baritone saxophone/song arranger Gary LeFebvre.
      00:28:47 End
      Start An unidentified jazz piece.
      00:13:22 An unidentified jazz band tunes before the performance. There is chatting in the background.
      00:15:11 A medley of "Greensleeves" and other melodies.
    - "Lion" - Joie Cook Gorton - Laurence Sarezky - Rick Kurshner - Richard Johnson, undated, AFC 2011/053: SR294; RXH 4180; 1 sound tape reel (00:36:08): analog, 7 1/2 ips, stereo; 7 in.
      According to accompanying documentation these songs were recorded in Sarezky and Kurshner's living room. Joie Cook Gorton (vocals, rhythm guitar), Laurence Sarezky (vocals, lead guitar), Rick Kurshner (backup harmony, drums), Richard Johnson (backup harmony, bass)
      Start An unidentified folk song sung by a female singer. Lyrics: "I know a man, I want him to be mine. All I can give you are the words of my soul now ... I am coming home, coming home."
      00:03:34 An unidentified folk song. Lyrics: "There is a small boy on the branches way up high on the top of the trees, and his mama calls come down this minute, but he learns what it is to be free"
      00:07:18 An unidentified folk song. Lyrics: "Do you want to dance, hold my hand, do you want to dance with me babe, we could dance under the moonlight, hug and kiss all through the night"
      00:11:08 An unidentified folk song. Lyrics: "...Sounding like a movie star staying as long as you can, someone you don't have to pretend...sounding like a lady that's going to be around...this perfect life"
      00:14:20 An unidentified folk song. Lyrics: "When I walk in yesterday, it was raining, I had nothing on, there is something in the back of my mind now, you must be doing something wrong"
      00:18:13 An unidentified folk song. Lyrics: "Guess I have to get used to love, give out myself, if you can't say I love you, you better stay awaysee how she run"
      00:21:38 An unidentified folk song. Lyrics: "Every morning half past nine, everybody gonna shine, every evening, from dinner time on, everybody drinking wine, it is our way"
      00:24:48 An unidentified folk song. Lyrics: "You make me feel alright, you are my sunshine"
      00:28:47 An unidentified instrumental folk song played by guitars, banjo and other instruments.
      00:30:00 An unidentified folk song. Lyrics: "Martha, Martha, where have you gone, you forgot a song, here is your song, my guitar goes weary, Sunday afternoon I am lonely, that's when I miss you the most"
      00:34:26 An unidentified folk song. Lyrics: "Mama said, hold on tight to me, too much fun for me, I can't wait to grow up...I can't wait till I am older ... How happy I will be"
      00:36:08 End
    - Lightnin' Hopkins interview, undated, AFC 2011/053: SR097; RXH 3235; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Side 1: 00:48:47; Side 2: 01:23:22): analog, 3 3/4 ips and 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      LC engineer's note: Side 1 - interview and music; Side 2 - mostly blues tracks. On Side 1, the speed changes constantly. On Side 2 the speed changes from 3 3/4 ips to 7 1/2 ips at 01:07:55:00, then goes back to 3 3/4 ips at 01:19:16:15.
      Start getting ready
      00:00:51 Start of the interview of LH by PW. LH says he was so small that he had to get up on a truck with his guitar in order to be seen when he performed.
      00:02:30 LH says that he was born on March 15, 1912. He says that when he was eight years old, he left home with a guitar around his neck. He initially went to Alabama and Mississippi. He also went to St. Louis and Chicago. He left brothers and sisters behind. He says that his mother is still alive.
      00:05:30 PW asks LH why he thought he was a good guitar player when he was right years old. LH responds. He says he played sometimes in the streets when he was a young man. He talks about some of the musicians he met, including Lonnie Johnson and Howlin' Wolf.
      00:07:45 PW asks LH if he remembers any blues singers coming through his part of the country when he was young. LH replies Bessie Smith but not Ma Rainey. He says he spent most of this time in Houston, Texas. He developed his own guitar style. He travelled a lot.
      00:09:20 PW ask what was it that made LH feel he wanted to play music. LH responds. He says that he cannot read music. He says all of his brothers had guitars and played. They had a family band. He says that he also played piano and organ, and a little bit of harp (harmonica).
      00:11:21 PW asks about the records LH made in the last 4 or 5 years. LH answers. He says he first recorded in Los Angeles. He talks about his experience making records. He says that he's made about 100 records.
      00:13:50 PW asks LH what he did when he stopped playing on the streets, how did he make his living. LH answers. He says he was in jail for a while for fighting.
      00:17:30 They talk about a scar on LH's leg from having to wear a ball and chain. LH says he had to work on a road gang.